We are going to be discussing what the primary zone is and what are the types, and also
we will be creating the primary zone in our next video using the DNS management console.
A primary DNS zone is the original red right autoitative DNS zone of a portion of a DNS
name speaks. So when a DNS server hosts the primary zone, that DNS server is considered
as the autoitative DNS server, and it is the primary source for information of that zone.
Zone of data possible only in the primary DNS zone, which means primary DNS zone is hosted
in the primary DNS server. So if, for example, the primary DNS server is unavailable, the
device will contact a secondary DNS server if your domain environment has a secondary DNS
server, which of course will continue with the end copy of the primary DNS record.
So a primary zone can be standard or active directory integrated zone. When you create it
for my standard zone, the database file is stored locally on a system 32 folder. In the system
32 folder, there's a DNS folder where you can find all these files. So all the changes
made to the zone out detailed to this file. The DNS server, that is autoitative for
the standard primary zone is a single master server that holds the red right zone data.
So if you have also configured a backup of this file or have a secondary, so created a
footage data from the primary zone, you won't be having any backup of this file of this
zone file. So when it is a server crash or this video in your domain environment, the zone
file of the totality lost. So I will show you with demonstrating how to create our first
from our DNS zone.